No limits. No fears. No substitutes.
GoldenEye is a adventure, action, thriller film directed by Martin Campbell.
When a powerful satellite system falls into the hands of Alec Trevelyan, AKA Agent 006, a former ally-turned-enemy, only James
Bond can save the world from a dangerous space weapon that -- in one short pulse -- could destroy the earth!
As Bond squares off against his former compatriot, he also battles Xenia
Onatopp, an assassin who uses pleasure as her ultimate weapon.
James Bond, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Alec Trevelyan, played by Sean Bean.
Natalya Simonova, played by Izabella Scorupco.
Xenia Onatopp, played by Famke Janssen.
Jack Wade, played by Joe Don Baker.
M, played by Judi Dench.
GoldenEye is a 1995 action spy film, the seventeenth in the James Bond series produced by Eon
Productions, and the first to star Pierce Brosnan as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
Directed by Martin Campbell, it was the first in the series not to use
any story elements from the works of novelist Ian Fleming.
GoldenEye was also the first James Bond film not produced by Albert R.
Broccoli, following his stepping down from Eon Productions and replacement
by his daughter, Barbara Broccoli (along with Michael G.
Wilson, although Broccoli was still involved as a consultant producer;
it was his final film project before his death in 1996).
The story was conceived and written by Michael France,
with later collaboration by other writers.
In the film, Bond fights to prevent rogue ex-MI6 agent Alec Trevelyan (Sean Bean) from
using a satellite weapon against London to cause a global financial collapse.
GoldenEye was released after a six-year hiatus in the series caused by legal disputes, during which Timothy Dalton's
contract for the role of James Bond expired and he decided to leave the role, being replaced by Brosnan.
M was also recast, actress Judi Dench becoming the first woman to
portray the character, replacing Robert Brown.
The role of Miss Moneypenny was also recast, Caroline
Bliss being replaced by Samantha Bond.
Desmond Llewelyn was the only actor to reprise his previous role, as Q.
It was the first Bond film made after the dissolution of the Soviet Union and the
end of the Cold War, which provided a background for the plot.
Principal photography for GoldenEye took place from January to June 1995 in the UK, Russia, Monte Carlo,
and Puerto Rico; it was the inaugural film production to be shot at Leavesden Studios.
The first Bond film to use computer-generated imagery (CGI), GoldenEye was also the final film in the
career of special effects supervisor Derek Meddings, and was dedicated to his memory.
The film accumulated a worldwide gross of over US$356 million, considerably better than any of the 1980s Bond films, without taking inflation
into account, to become the fourth-highest grossing film of 1995 and the highest-grossing James Bond film since Moonraker (1979).
It received positive reviews from critics, with Brosnan viewed as a
worthy successor to Sean Connery's portrayal as Bond.
It also received award nominations for Best Special Visual Effects and Best
Sound from the British Academy of Film and Television Arts.
It was followed by Tomorrow Never Dies in 1997.
The film explores themes of computer virus, cuba, falsely
accused, secret intelligence service, secret identity.
The tone is intense.